Alex Theobold Web Developer

github.com/theoboldalex 07858 593 903

alextheobold.com

theoboldalex@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a Web Developer specialising in building data backed web applications with tools including Laravel, VueJs and MySQL. I have been in the industry since 2020 after a career change from operations management within a global fin-tech organisation and I am passionate about collaborating with people and organisations that believe in delivering quality and value to their customers.

SKILLS

Languages: PHP, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Laravel, Vue, JQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Tools: Git, Linux, Jenkins, Heroku

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase

EXPERIENCE

Fancensus.com Ltd - Web Developer

March 2021 - Present

Working closely with product stakeholders in the video games and consumer software distribution industry, I contributed to the modernisation of a legacy enterprise customer reporting portal and support ticketing system.

Intelligent Bodymorphic Dynamics Ltd - Web Developer

2020 - 2021

Contributed to a greenfield project in the entertainment and streaming subscriptions space, encompassing aspects of social media and ecommerce.

SI Risk Ltd - Senior Operations Coordinator

2019 - 2020

Overseeing daily operations of a Security Operations Center and managing multiple client relationships. During my tenure with SI Risk, I helped the business to implement ISO 27001 Data Security control measures and developed a range of technical documentation and training materials for business critical systems.

Thomson Reuters - Operations Team Lead

2014 - 2019

Management of project delivery and strategy for a portfolio of Global financial institutions. While in this role, I delivered a project from idea to implementation which increased quarterly profits by over 22%.

EDUCATION

Level 3 Diploma in Leadership and Management - ILM

2015 - 2017

BA (Hons) English - Manchester Metropolitan University

2009 - 2014

Grade - 2:1